TAMEKA STEVENSON

San Diego, CA (remote) | LinkedIn

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

U.S. Navy veteran pivoting from healthcare to software development, bringing along fine-tuned problem solving skills, attention to detail, and the desire to experience personal and professional growth in a team environment. Dedicated, fast learner who is adept in an array of scripting languages, development tools, and agile project management practices.

SKILLS SUMMARY

- HTML & CSS
- Javascript
- Bootstrap
- Postman

- PostgreSQL
- Ruby / Ruby on Rails
- React / React on Rails
- JSON

- RESTful architecture
- Test-driven development
- Debugging
- Git version control

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SCIENTIST.COM — Solana Beach, CA (remote) Full Stack Developer (Intern)

Jun 2022 - Jul 2022

- Improved knowledge and use of Github project management tools, such as milestones, wikis, and automated triggers, during weekly sprint planning.
- Organized supplier list by accessing data in Redux store and using Javascript to manipulate it accordingly.
- Completed user-friendly, responsive styling of ads from an external source using Block-Element-Modifier CSS methods.

LEARN ACADEMY — San Diego, CA (remote)

Mar 2022 - Jul 2022

Full Stack Developer (Student)

- Acquired foundational knowledge of understanding programming languages, reading documentation, manipulating databases, and code debugging.
- Achieved proficiency in delivering valuable products via pair-programming and use of scrum methodology.
- Volunteered as a teacher's assistant and mentor to aspiring developers that register for LEARN Academy's Jumpstart and Bootcamp, respectively.

UNITED STATES NAVY — Various Locations

Sep 2011 - Mar 2021

Epidemiology Team Lead

- Directed and evaluated a team of 10 contact tracers on investigations into regional SARS-CoV2 outbreaks.
- Developed a PDF fillable intake form to streamline contact tracing, reducing use of manpower from one-hour per patient to 15 minutes per patient.
- Educated over 100 medical staff on established protective measures to prevent the spread of SARS-CoV2 while maintaining adequate patient care.

Certified Pharmacy Technician

- Prepared intravenous solutions, admixtures, respiratory drugs and other solutions using aseptic techniques.
- Consulted with and advised patients and providers on specified use and potential side effects of prescribed medications.
- Troubleshot pharmacy hardware and software (e.g. Pyxis, ScriptPro), minimizing pharmacy downtime.

Senior Medical Department Representative

- Trained 30 uniformed personnel on department policies and procedures to maximize efficiency and accuracy during patient care.
- Administered vaccinations, collected blood specimens, and managed physical and electronic medical records for over 250 service members.
- Provided triage, first-aid and referral to outside medical providers during workplace injury or medical emergency.

EDUCATION

LIBERTY UNIVERSITY, M.A.in Medical Sciences, May 2023

LEARN ACADEMY, Certificate of Completion in Full Stack Software Development, July 2022

NORTHERN VERMONT UNIVERSITY, B.S. in Wellness & Alternative Medicine, May 2019

MIDLANDS TECHNICAL COLLEGE, A.S. in Computer Programming, December 2012

MIDLANDS TECHNICAL COLLEGE, A.A.S. in Biology, December 2012